Ren Burnett

Adaptable fullstack developer with attention to detail and the ability to empathetically and thoughtfully collaborate. Excited to bring traits gained in six years as a precision technician to help shape quality code. Enthusiastic about learning new technologies/languages and developing helpful, practical software.

Seattle, WA (206) 669-7498 renardburnett@gmail.com github.com/renburnett linkedin.com/in/renard-burnett-ii renburnett.com

PROJECTS

Grasher — Food Inventory Tracker

grasher-food-tracker-frontend.herokuapp.com github.com/renburnett/grasher-app-frontend

- React frontend, Rails API backend, Semantic-React for styling
- Login: r@r.com Pass: 123

KEXP Song Favoriter — *Track User's Favorite Songs* **kexp-song-favoriter-rails.herokuapp.com**

github.com/renburnett/kexp song favoriter

- Static web app implemented with Ruby on Rails
- Queries KEXP endpoint
- Persists songs and users to Postgres DB

Customer Review Parser — Crawl/Scrape For Customer Reviews

- Scrapes customer reviews from Amazon and Windows online stores
- Data is stripped of unwanted characters and saved to an Azure DB-finally it's visualized in PowerBI and setup an Azure DevOps CI/CD pipeline

Chatter! — ChatRoom WebApp

github.com/kel29/chat-frontend

- React-based fronted, Rails API backend
- ActionCables and React ActionCable Provider to handle connections
- Bootstrap used for styling

EXPERIENCE

Amazon via Collabera, Composite Technician — Seattle

MARCH 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2019

Worked as a technician on an R&D team to assemble, re-work and layup carbon fiber parts for package delivery drones.

Microsoft via WTIA, Software Developer Apprentice — Redmond

NOVEMBER 2017 - NOVEMBER 2018

Worked on OS Bluetooth Quality team for first six months where I created a Bluetooth Radio Provisioning tool that is now used to set up mock peripherals for testing against the Windows OS. Reduced the time spent testing by one to two hours. The remaining six months was spent on a Data Science team. Enjoyed learning from teammates and problem solving alongside them.

Boeing, Composite Technician and Team Lead — Everett

MARCH 2011 - APRIL 2017

Team leader of a fast-paced seven person Composite Repair Team. Interactions with teammates were professional, respectful and fun. Ensured that majority of deadlines were met but not at the expense of quality work.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript

React

HTML5/CSS

Git

C#/ASP.NET

Python

Ruby on Rails

MVC Architecture

SQL

Azure

EDUCATION

Flatiron School — Software Engineering Certificate

AUGUST 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

 Functional and Object Oriented Programming with JavaScript and Ruby.

Code Fellows — Fullstack Developer Certificate

JUNE 2017 - SEPTEMBER 2017

- Learned to design and create single page web applications from scratch using MVC architecture.
- Worked with string, array, object data structures and algorithms to solve code challenges with vanilla JavaScript.